<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Museum</string>
    <string name="title_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_level">Exhibits</string>
    <string name="title_dashboard">Displays</string>
    <string name="title_notifications">Map</string>
    <string name="exhibit_detail">Exhibit</string>
    <string name="placeholder_text">
        "Placeholder\n\n\n\n\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="first_inhabitants_text">
        "First Inhabitants\n\n"

        "For thousands of years, native peoples traversed land that would become Frederick County. "
        "Historic-era tribes, such as the Susquehannock, Piscataway, and Tuscarora, used the Upper "
        "Potomac and Monocacy River, with surrounding valleys, to hunt wild game and establish small "
        "encampments and villages.\n\n"

        "A watercolor by English artist John White shows a fortified village. The houses are covered "
        "\"some wth matts, and some wth barcks of trees,\" according to White's inscription at the bottom "
        "of the drawing. Residents gather around the fire at the center of the town. A few people can be "
        "seen carrying a bow, another an axe; a dog is seen in the upper left.\n\n"

    </string>
    <string name="colonial_life_text">
        "Colonial Life\n\n"

        "In the New World, faith and frugality were guiding principles. Several churches were established "
        "in early Fredericktowne. These served for religious purposes and as centers for education and "
        "social life. The distinct cultures of these early settlers were illustrated by the diverse "
        "architectural designs, styles of dress, cooking traditions and festivities.\n\n"

        "John Thomas Schley (1712-1790) emigrated from Moerzheim, Germany around 1745, and built the "
        "first house in Frederick. He became a naturalized citizen in 1760. Schley was a schoolmaster, "
        "tavern owner, organist, and composer. He was very active in the Reformed Church and was a founding "
        "member of the first fire company in Frederick.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="establishment_text">
        "Establishment of Frederick County\n\n"

        "Europeans established the provincial colony of Maryland in 1634, consisting of settlements "
        "along the Chesapeake Bay and Potomac River in southern Maryland. Slowly, the English colonists "
        "would move toward the interior of the colony, establishing villages along major waterways connecting "
        "to the Potomac and the Bay. The area here was seen by English settlers as untamed, wild and dangerous. "
        "Land speculators and colonial officials wanted to take control of the interior, making these areas "
        "profitable for themselves and the English throne. One such, was Daniel Dulany, an Irish lawyer and "
        "entrepreneur who had possession of a land patent of 7,000 acres adjacent the Monocacy River by the "
        "name of \"Tasker's Chance.\"\n\n"

        "Daniel Dulany knew he could not successfully settle his new community on Maryland's western frontier "
        "with typical English immigrants. He knew Pennsylvania had success in developing its interior thanks to "
        "immigrants from Germany. These people were hard-working, brave and industrious. Over several years, Dulany "
        "sent inducements to German and Swiss peoples in Pennsylvania and Europe to settle on his Tasker's Chance "
        "parcel. Meanwhile, English and Scots-Irish began migrating to Frederick-Town, coming from established towns "
        "and counties of the colony. Frederick-Town would become the county seat.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="craftspeople_text">
        "Craftspeople\n\n"

        "Fredericktowne became a thriving community, attracting many tradespeople, such as weavers, tailors, "
        "silversmiths, shoemakers, tanners, blacksmiths, potters, and wheelwrights. About seven out of eight citizens "
        "were farmers, and other professionals ranged from newspaper publishers to innkeepers. As the town grew, "
        "talented craftspeople helped establish Fredericktowne as a notable crossroads where makers of glass, furniture, "
        "clocks, jewelry, and hats could be found. These locally made items contributed to the resident's quality of life.\n\n "

        "E. Frederick Klein was born in Wurtemberg, Germany. In 1790, After serving as a baker in the army in Switzerland, "
        "he sailed to America and, for two years, worked as a baker in Pennsylvania. For 19 years, he ran a bakery in Baltimore. "
        "Due to ill health, he moved to Frederick County in 1840.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="revolutionary_text">
        "Revolutionary War\n\n"

        "Residents of varying cultures banded together in the 1770s in their fight for independence. The American Revolution "
        "attracted a new wave of Europeans to settle in Fredericktowne in a most unorthodox manner. These were the Hessians, "
        "German mercenary soldiers hired by the British to fight in the American Revolutionary War. Some were captured at the "
        "battles of Saratoga, New York, and Yorktown, Virginia, and were imprisoned in the Frederick Barracks in the south area "
        "of town. Finding friendly residents who shared their native tongue, many Hessian soldiers made Frederick their home at "
        "war's end, rather than return to Europe.\n\n"

        "Conrad Engelbrecht (1758-1819), a tailor from Eichig, near present-day Bayreuth, Germany. He was a Hessian soldier "
        "hired by the British to suppress the Revolutionary War. He was the father of Jacob Engelbrecht and is buried across "
        "the street from this museum in the Evangelical Lutheran Church graveyard. Jacob Engelbrecht (1797-1882), served Frederick "
        "as a tailor, musician and major. He was also a diarist, whose observations are valuable today for its many perspectives.\n\n"
    </string>

    <string name="blackfrederick_text">
        "Black Frederick\n\n"

        "Upon the establishment of Frederick County by European settlers in the 18th century, African descended people were both "
        "free and enslaved. Many fugitive Blacks formed Maroon communities with local Native Americans before the arrival of the English. "
        "African Americans labored in agriculture, industry, were skilled artisans, and engaged in business. Blacks advanced Frederick County "
        "during the colonial era and into the Revolutionary War both on and off the battlefield. \n\n"

        "After the war for independence, the population of free Blacks in the Frederick region grew. This inspired greater abolitionist "
        "efforts as well as severe laws passed to restrict the freedoms of all African Americans. Despite this, free Blacks established "
        "crucial organizations for social, cultural, religious educational and economic upliftment including the Underground Railroad "
        "during the 19th century.\n\n"

        "With the Civil War, the status of African Americans changed drastically as over 3,000 Blacks from Frederick fought for freedom "
        "in the conflict. The Reconstruction Era in Frederick witnessed an explosion of churches, cemeteries, schools, political associations, "
        "and the establishment of Black towns throughout the county.\n\n"

        "As Reconstruction ended, the 'Jim Crow' era heralded in segregation and the violent treatment of African Americans in Frederick County. "
        "This was met by the Frederick Black community with the creation of important institutions to address the needs of African American citizens "
        "in medicine, education, religion, culture, economics, politics, and social concerns while simultaneously fighting in both World Wars. As the "
        "Civil Rights Era progressed, Black Frederick residents were exceptionally active in national and local efforts to end segregation and attain "
        "equal rights for all. The collective struggle Black Fredericktonians to ensure justice and equality in Frederick and beyond has continued to "
        "the present.\n\n "
    </string>
</resources>